[SITARA] But this must be
the moment
I've been waiting for.
[gasps] How so?
What could we hope
to accomplish?
I have great knowledge.
If you'll allow,
I'll serve you as your
new Jada stone, Highness.
Please, just lend me your power.
And the two of us
can summon a fierce storm.
[insects trilling]
[Sitara sighs softly]
What have I done?
Not only did I ignore
Princess Sorghaghtani's
orders...
[gasps softly] Hold on,
I'm not...
♪
[gasps]
I'm not her slave, am I?
Ah, there you are. Fatima!
[SITARA] Lady Töregene
and I have suffered greatly,
but she's been forced
to bear her pain
far longer than mine.
-[SHIRA] Hey.
-Which is why...
Tell this
to Princess Sorghaghtani.
I've found my way
into a much more
convenient position out here.
Uh, is that right?
Well, all the better then.
[SITARA] No need to worry.
I understand now.
I know what I must do.
[Shira exhales]
[SITARA]
So just you wait, Mongols.
♪
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[groans] Uh?
♪
Uh, what's all this, Chagatai?
[Ögedei groans]
I offer you
my deepest apologies.
[ÖGEDEI AND ILÜGE] Huh?
First, I challenged
the Great Kha'an to a wager.
Then I displayed the utmost
insolence by actually winning.
Oh, you mean that?
[ÖGEDEI] Oh...
For this grave offense,
I am prepared to be flogged
or even to receive
a death sentence.
Please do with me as you will.
Hm?
[chuckles] You are forgiven,
my brother.
You know
I am not angered so easily.
Uh?
Ögedei Kha'an
has shown me his mercy!
Let us all praise
his noble benevolence!
[ALL] Huzzah!
Huzzah!
-Huh? What is all this?
- Huzzah!
-Huh?
-I now take my leave.
I swear,
why did Chagatai do all that?
[CHINQAI] The prince put on
that performance for your sake.
[ÖGEDEI] Chinqai?
As one who only recently
took the throne,
honor upon your name
is of the greatest importance.
And what quality is prized most
among steppe tribe leaders?
Benevolence?
Exactly. Cruel to his foes,
and benevolent to his subjects.
You've now proven yourself
to be precisely that.
Well, I suppose it makes sense.
But why be so dramatic?
Huh?
Now I understand.
-[birds screeching]
-Benevolence, indeed.
♪
[SITARA (ADULT)] Kurultais were
held under Ögedei Kha'an
to discuss matters
concerning future policies.
And in the Mongol Empire,
the emperor's consorts took part
in these political matters
as well.
[Kirgistani grunts]
Töregene?
What are you doing,
attending a Kurultai?
You're hardly ever at these.
Am I not permitted?
Some would give anything
to be here but cannot.
[MÖGE] Hmph!
[ÖGEDEI] Uh? [chuckles]
[MÖGE] Uh? [chuckles]
♪
-Listen, Uqai.
-My name's Otai.
Please try to remember that,
dear Father.
[TEMÜGE] Mm...
Today's meeting will outline
our next military campaign.
Soon, we'll head eastward
and target the Jin Dynasty.
[OTAI] From what I've heard,
they're responsible
for abducting and killing
many of our forefathers.
Yes, but that's frankly
of little consequence
at this point.
House Tolui
has the largest army.
But House Chagatai
has the Kha'an's trust.
The head of House Jochi is dead
and his territory's far away.
Whereas the lands of my House
of Temüge
are close to the Jin's domain.
Because our houses rule
over quite a large number
of subjects as of now,
we all want roles for ourselves
that won't incur losses.
So I'm wondering
how the new Kha'an
will attempt to appease
each one of us.
Thoughts. Daritai?
Otai, Father.
[all murmuring]
Yes, true.
How will you handle
such an important matter,
Great Kha'an?
[Ögedei inhales]
I wish to build a great capital.
[ALL] Huh?
[CHAGATAI] Uh-oh.
[all gasp]
A capital, huh?
Indeed, a capital.
We will construct a city
in the steppe.
One made of permanent buildings,
rather than our tents.
Ah! What are you going on about?
What of the campaign
to bring down the Jin?
A capital, you say?
Do we all have to live there?
[VASSAL 1] We Mongols
take pride in crossing mountains
in pursuit of unseen lands.
[VASSAL 2] Live like
settled people? Disgusting.
Everyone, the Great Kha'an
hasn't finished speaking yet.
[ÖGEDEI] It will be a capital,
but not one for us to live in.
Workshops will be provided there
for crafting weapons
and jewelry.
It will also serve
as a trading post
where merchants can gather.
We will all continue
our nomadic lifestyles.
But at times,
we will visit and spend freely.
In a show of our grace
and benevolence.
When word spreads
of such a place,
it's sure to attract
people and goods
from across the land.
What say you?
This doesn't make
any sense at all.
[all murmuring]
[exhales] Will it not work?
Hmm...
[TOLUI] Sounds great to me!
♪
It's quite a curious proposal,
and one worth doing.
[chuckles] Tolui.
Tell me, Great Kha'an.
When will we all
discuss the matter of war?
[ÖGEDEI] Uh?
[Kirgistani grunts] Huh?
Now the time is ripe to destroy
our sworn foes, the Jin.
[TOLUI] Their formerly
vast territory has shrunk,
so they're cornered
like tiny rats.
And dealing the last blow
will be our Great Kha'an!
[Ögedei chuckles]
[TOLUI] This war will be just
like a circle hunt.
Our quarry...
The Jin capital, Kaifeng.
The Great Kha'an will set up
camp across the Yellow River,
directly to the north of it.
While the rats tremble in fear,
we'll pincer them
from the south.
That sounds more like hunting
deer than rats, if you ask me.
Call them fawns if you prefer.
Tolui, you mustn't
underestimate them.
Though on the verge of collapse,
the Jin vastly outnumber us
in both soldiers and subjects.
[Tolui laughs]
Which is why I want you
to begin attacking
from the east and have
their citizens running, Uncle.
[TEMÜGE] Hmm?
[TOLUI] Just like you would
coax animals
into a hunting circle.
If we can chase the rest
of the Jin populace
inside Kaifeng's walls,
all those soldiers and subjects
you mentioned
will be trapped in a city
that's completely closed off.
After winter passes
and all their food runs out,
I wonder what state
their poor town will be in.
[laughs]
[Chagatai clears throat]
Oh, uh, as for you, brother...
I think it's best if you
stay here and look after things.
We should leave
our precious homeland
to the one the Great Kha'an
trusts more than anyone, right?
[ÖGEDEI] Hm.
Well, that's fine.
♪
Jochi's kin will not have a part
to play here, I'm afraid.
[ORDA] Huh?
In exchange for this,
you will be leading some of our
other campaigns to the west.
[ORDA] Mm...
[TOLUI] How does that sound?
Are any of you unhappy
with these war plans?
-[CHINQAI] Prince Tolui.
-Huh?
In order to approach Kaifeng
from the south,
our warriors will be forced
into Southern Song territory.
And through precipitous
mountain roads at that.
It won't be a problem.
The Southern Song are enemies
of the Jin, too,
which makes them a friend to us.
Now as for
the precipitous mountains...
we'll prevail.
[TÖREGENE] That's everything
they discussed at the Kurultai.
Thank you very much.
If Tolui's plans
eventually succeed,
starvation and cold will await
the people of Kaifeng.
I'm confronted
with this knowledge,
yet I still...
-[breathes shakily]
-Sitara,
do you feel unwell?
You're trembling.
[Sitara gasps]
[stutters] I'm all right.
My apologies.
Sitara...
Lady Töregene,
I would prefer it
if you called me Fatima, please.
Fatima?
Sitara is my name
from when I was a slave.
It'd be improper
for somebody of low birth
to serve the
Great Kha'an's consort.
[Töregene sighs]
I, too, pass myself off
as a Naiman here.
[SITARA] Uh?
[TÖREGENE]
After marrying a Merkit man,
I would naturally
call myself one as well.
But there are
quite a few Mongols
who don't take kindly to them.
That's why I chose
to hide my past,
and kept it a secret
from everyone I could.
[Sitara gasps]
Please keep it
a secret, too, Fatima.
[SITARA] I will.
She has the scent
of danger about her.
So then, where do we go
from here?
First, there is indeed
a power imbalance
between the Great Kha'an
and Tolui family.
The House of Tolui commands
the largest Mongol army.
The Great Kha'an has authority.
And the House of Chagatai
supports him.
We must cause a rift
between them.
But in order to do that,
Prince Tolui's big plan
will need to go off
successfully.
♪
[Boraqchin coughs]
[MÖGE] Pardon the intrusion.
[chuckles]
How are you feeling, Boraqchin?
Well, seeing your face
has certainly
brightened my mood a little.
What do you have there?
This is a medical text
brought here
by Quanzhen Daoists.
[MÖGE] Hmm...
Just through the process
of living,
our bodies gradually lose
their qi,
which leads
to maladies and death.
But through a specific training,
you can stop the flow
of qi entirely.
It appears
that is their technique
for achieving immortality.
[Möge exhales]
Will those techniques return you
to your former health,
Boraqchin?
Möge.
It's just that you are supposed
to be the one sitting
at the Great Kha'an's side
at Kurultais.
And we desperately need
your clever mind.
[BORAQCHIN] Hmm.
Worry not.
Kurultais aren't the only way
to decide things.
[MÖGE] Huh?
[BORAQCHIN]
What's most important is
to discreetly maneuver
all manner of affairs.
And now then,
tell me about everything
you have heard lately.
[Möge chuckles]
[SITARA] Prince Tolui's plan
puts most of the burden
on himself.
But should he succeed,
he will also earn
the most acclaim.
I believe he will
most likely succeed.
After all, the House of Tolui
does have the strongest army
of the Mongols.
The Mongol army typically
employs audacious tactics,
which will startle the enemy.
However...
However,
the other Mongol princes
will reach the same conclusion.
The House of Tolui...
[BOTH]...is too powerful.
[Möge gasps]
Even if Tolui doesn't intend
to betray anyone,
should the Houses begin
to fear his strength,
and harbor distrust
toward him...
and should they decide
to collude
against the House of Tolui,
I am certain...
[SITARA]
The Mongols will fracture.
And eventually fall to ruin.
[BORAQCHIN] There will be those
who aim to sow
the seeds of discord.
But then, what can we do?
Möge...
You are still young
and beautiful, unlike me.
And honest and amiable.
[MÖGE] Uh...
[BORAQCHIN] To ensure
the Mongols are not divided,
and to ensure
our hearts remain as one,
I need you to take steps
in my stead.
[MÖGE] Hmm.
I'll do what you need
of me, Boraqchin.
♪
[SITARA]
Driven into a closed-off city
to ultimately perish
from hunger and cold.
The people of Tus
could have met the same fate.
To the citizens of Kaifeng,
I'd be no different
than any other Mongol.
♪
The Great Kha'an
heads off to war,
and Prince Chagatai stays
to watch the steppe.
What shall we be doing
during this time?
[TÖREGENE] We will accompany
the Great Kha'an's army
to the front-line camp.
Chagatai is here now
to say his farewells
to the Great Kha'an.
Once we depart,
we probably won't be seeing him
for quite a long time.
[SITARA] To cause turmoil
among the Mongols,
we need a faction that will
oppose the House of Tolui.
The House of Chagatai is
an indispensable part of that.
Well then, please allow me
to go to him as your messenger,
and give Prince Chagatai
our warmest regards.
I, Fatima,
am your humble servant.
[QADAQ] Hmm?
[cattle mooing]
[hammering]
[indistinct chatter]
[horse neighs]
Hold on. Why are you
following me, Sir Qadaq?
I can't let you go by yourself.
Oh, I never took you
to be such a gentleman.
No, I'm saying
I don't trust you.
Lady Töregene trusts me,
isn't that enough?
Well, she's not the one I serve.
So it's a long story.
But I'm actually acting
on someone else's ord...
[gasps]
[Sitara pants]
[MÖGE] Hey! Aren't you
Töregene's slave?
Yes, you there.
What are you doing out here?
[Sitara gasps] This woman...
is Lady Möge, the fourth wife
of the Great Kha'an!
Oh. I see.
You just don't learn, do you?
[Sitara gasps, whimpers]
Are you lost again?
-Hm?
-You are lost, aren't you?
I know! I bet you're
still struggling
to learn the locations
of all the tents in our camp.
I've had my suspicions
ever since you got caught
wandering around
and Töregene had to make up
an excuse for you.
-Or maybe...
-Fine, you figured it out.
-[cries]
-That's what I thought.
-What should I do?
-Hmm.
I'll bring shame
upon Lady Töregene
and be scolded again.
It's no business of mine
if Töregene scolds you.
But bringing shame to the
Great Kha'an is another thing.
Allow me to show you the way.
[exclaims] Really? I can't
thank you enough, Lady Möge.
I need to figure
a way out of this.
Something about her
seems different than last time.
-The earrings.
-[Möge gasps]
Uh... I'm so sorry.
Do I look odd without them?
Oh, no, I wouldn't say
you look "odd."
-But...
-[Möge sighs]
[SITARA] Did you happen
to misplace them recently?
[Möge grunts]
No.
The Great Kha'an chose
to sell them.
[POOR MAN] Great Kha'an!
Oh, Great Kha'an, I beg of you
to buy this melon from me.
I am just ever so impoverished.
It's so small.
Möge, please give this man
those earrings you're wearing.
[MÖGE] What!
[poor man exclaims]
[laughs]
[ÖGEDEI] Worry not, Möge.
I truly believe
that those earrings
are destined to return
to you in the future.
He said they'll return?
What could he have meant
by that?
I don't know in the least.
I still cannot understand the
Great Kha'an in the slightest.
-[CHINQAI] Lady Möge!
-Mm?
Lady Möge,
the Great Kha'an calls for you.
What does he want?
I wasn't informed
of the details.
-[exhales] Chuu!
-[horse neighs]
[ÖGEDEI]
It shouldn't be long now.
[hooves clopping]
Oh, there she is.
Greetings, Möge.
Come sit here.
I have here a gift for you.
[Möge gasps]
[MÖGE] It can't be.
[Sitara gasps]
[Möge exclaiming]
But these are my earrings!
[ÖGEDEI] Where did you manage
to obtain these?
That would be Khorasan.
While I was on my journey
to Samarkand,
I was fortunate enough
to meet a trader who told me
that he had some fine treasures
from the east.
Might I interest you in these?
I asked him where he ever
could have come across
such magnificent pearl earrings.
He said that he found them
in a Uyghur city
by a random stroke of luck.
-He received them...
-Please, sir.
...from a poor man on the verge
of starving to death,
in exchange
for a few loaves of bread.
So Khorasan, huh?
That's further than I expected.
I believe earrings
as splendid as these
truly befit the grand conqueror
of the world.
That is why
I came here immediately
to present them as an offering,
Great Kha'an.
[MÖGE]
They really did return to me.
Thank you
for delivering them to me.
I will buy all of your goods,
and your fellow merchants'
as well.
[exclaims] Thank you very much.
All of them?
Bring me more of your wares
in the future.
You will not regret it.
[CHINQAI] Uh...
Uh... Ah, over there will do.
Just put them
with all the others.
Be careful handling that.
[TRADER 1] I didn't expect him
to buy everything from us.
Coming to Mongolia
was the right decision.
[SITARA] Excuse me.
[TRADERS] Hmm?
My apologies.
You traveled here from Khorasan?
[ABD] We did. Who are you?
I originally hail
from Khorasan as well.
Why have you made your way
all the way to Mongolia?
You're asking why?
It is simple.
Because Mongolia is where
the most profit
is to be had, of course.
We had figured that
the Mongol emperor would be
more likely than most
to offer high prices for wares
coming from Khorasan
and points west.
But weren't you afraid
to come here?
The journey is a long one,
and the Mongols
are a frightening people.
Not at all. In fact, it is safer
to travel now than before.
[Sitara gasps]
The Mongols appoint officials to
govern the lands they conquer.
Their duty is to protect
merchants passing through them.
[TRADER] The emperor is
a remarkable man, indeed.
[ÖGEDEI]
Thanks to your lovely earrings,
I have learned that
all is functioning as it should.
♪
[ÖGEDEI]
I have to wonder, though.
Will people come
to see it my way
after we have defeated
all the Jin?
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[SITARA (ADULT)] Next time,
"Great Khatun Boraqchin."